<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Always SWERVING to steer free of obstacles</title>
    <description>x75&#39;s experimental blog and general meme dump.</description>
    <link>http://x75.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://x75.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 11:13:57 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 11:13:57 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>From snowboarding to motion, music, and robotics</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-snowboarding-to-motion-music-and-robotics&quot;&gt;From snowboarding to motion, music, and robotics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: motion, robot learning, exploration, music&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently while browsing my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redbulletin.com/at/de/the-red-bulletin-magazin&quot;&gt;favorite robotics magazine&lt;/a&gt; I started reading an interview with Travis Rice, which I didn’t know, promoting his recent film &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefourthphase.com/&quot;&gt;The Fourth Phase&lt;/a&gt;. It’s usual that athletes mention issues interesting to robotics when talking about their body and the challenges involved in particular stunts, which is the reason why RB in fact is my fav’ed robotics mag in the first place. What struck me about this interview though that Travis just didn’t stop dropping major agreeable insights about motion and environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://x75.github.io/assets/20161109_rb_rice/rbrice_01_IMG_20161103_091430_400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Snowboarding and music&quot; title=&quot;Snowboarding and music&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://x75.github.io/assets/20161109_rb_rice/rbrice_02_IMG_20161103_091444_400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Topography, saliency, navigation&quot; title=&quot;Topography, saliency, navigation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![Topography, saliency, navigation](http://x75.github.io/assets/20161109_rb_rice/rbrice_03_IMG_20161103_091455_400.jpg “”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![Topography, saliency, navigation](http://x75.github.io/assets/20161109_rb_rice/rbrice_04_IMG_20161103_091506_400.jpg “”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![Topography, saliency, navigation](http://x75.github.io/assets/20161109_rb_rice/rbrice_05_IMG_20161103_091511_400.jpg “”)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://x75.github.io/2016/11/09/motion-music-robotics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://x75.github.io/2016/11/09/motion-music-robotics/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apparent uselessness</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;apparent-uselessness-the-illusion-of-progress-and-the-difficulty-of-finding-your-way&quot;&gt;Apparent uselessness, the illusion of progress, and the difficulty of finding your way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: robot epistemology, robot learning, exploration, dominant progressivist narratives, undreamed-of-utility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime last year I picked up on Kenneth Stanley’s and Joel Lehmann’s
2015 book called &lt;a href=&quot;http://mythoftheobjective.com/&quot;&gt;Why Greatness Cannot Be Planned - The Myth of the
Objective&lt;/a&gt;. In the book they develop an argument for an advanced
teleology based on experiments with synthetic processes of knowledge
acquisition in the context of AI, ALife, and Learning. The argument
roughly says, that if you want to reach a goal, that is ambitious in
the sense that the &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; sequence of steps (the route) which will
get you there, is not known, then accumulating possible steps is a
better strategy than heading directly into the direction of the
goal. That’s because chances are, that some of these steps will turn
out, but unforseeably so, to be precisely what is needed to make the
next move when negotiating the route. So far so good, I agree with this line of reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, additional manifestations of that same idea keep
popping up urging the collector inside me to collect. Here we
go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt; Stanley and Lehmann argue that, considering results on
“novelty search” in learning experiments with artificial agents,
unreflected measures of the distance to a given “goal” are bound to
get you stuck in a local extremum in all but trivial cases &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1939&lt;/strong&gt; Abraham Flexner’s article “The usefulness of useless
knowledge” &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, published in Harper’s issue 179 June/November 1939 (available online as &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.ias.edu/files/UsefulnessHarpers.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;). Flexner curiously sketches out a similar line of argument as
Stanley and Lehmann reinvigorating satisfaction of &lt;em&gt;curiosity&lt;/em&gt; as a sufficient and ultimately fruitful guide in the pursuit of knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;198X&lt;/strong&gt; The field of media archaeology has been promoting the stance
that complex techno-mathematical media can only be understood by
reconstructing original forward-looking perspectives and
emphasizing the genealogical importance of developments which
became “dead media” only in hindsight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt; Nicholas Nassim Taleb, deserving a separate comment on the black
swan idea (2007), meticulously expounds the difference of the
forward and the retrospective narration and substantializes the
phenomenon of unpredictability in the domain of complex systems (Extremistan). Honouring
this fundamental unpredictabilty we should be highly doubtful
about our ability to predict the future utility of any given idea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is an open list and this entry is a placeholder for things to
come …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realizing the validity of this issue there are fundamental
consequences for many areas of human activity, two of which are:
autonomous robotic learning (no universal recipe) and funding of
professional and amateur scientific pursuits (no maps for uncharted
territory &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spectrum-of-difficulties-in-reaching-goals&quot;&gt;Spectrum of difficulties in reaching goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on my own understanding of different learning problems for
artificial agents there exists a spectrum of difficulty, open to the
top, along which learning tasks can be positioned. In that spectrum we
can draw a line somewhere separating two types of such
problems. &lt;strong&gt;Update [2016-11-03]&lt;/strong&gt;: There is a direct correspondence here
with the complexity of functional relationships which could be ordered
like linear, monotonic, non-monotonic, zero/random. The line that I am
referring to above goes through the spectrum between monotonic and
non-monotonic problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are those problems, in which the goal-seeker (agent) and the
goal are alone in “free space”, meaning that the goal is visible to
the agent and the goal can be reached by following a monotonic
gradient, that is, by greedily reducing the distance on all axes of
space independently, reducing the problem to finding out about the
effects of the primitive actions (SMP) available to the agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other type are those in which other objects, usually referred to
as obstacles, are present in the same space. Here already no universal
recipe whatsoever can be given on how to reach the goal without
exploring the space first and building a map. In order to reach a goal
or desired destination, the distance to the goal has to increase on at
least one axis of the given space at some point
(non-monotonicity). This means, that if the wrong distance measure is
used, you easily end up in a local extremum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue also seems related to a) convexity, leaving the respective
reasoning and diagram as an exercise for a possible later post, and b)
to Franz &amp;amp; Mallot’s navigation hierarchy from their 2000 paper &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;

/**
*  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
*  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables*/
/*
var disqus_config = function () {
this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page&#39;s canonical URL variable
this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page&#39;s unique identifier variable
};
*/
(function() { // DON&#39;T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE
var d = document, s = d.createElement(&#39;script&#39;);
s.src = &#39;//x75.disqus.com/embed.js&#39;;
s.setAttribute(&#39;data-timestamp&#39;, +new Date());
(d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
})();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;#spectrum-of-difficulties-in-reaching-goals&quot;&gt;this section&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Thanks Giulio Sandini. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Please describe in precise steps how you are going to reach an
objective (draw a route on a map), which at best is likely to exist
and usually is only a vision, and where no one has gone before (on
parts of the map labelled “Terra incognita”). &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Biomimetic robot navigation. M. Franz, and H. Mallot. Robotics and Autonomous Systems 30 (1-2): 133-153 (2000) &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://x75.github.io/2016/10/06/apparent-uselessness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://x75.github.io/2016/10/06/apparent-uselessness/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rara Avis out on ALKU, ALKU099</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;rara-avis-music-cassette-mc-and-booklet-both-screaming-yellow-out-now-on-alku&quot;&gt;Rara Avis Music Cassette (MC) and booklet, both screaming yellow, out now on ALKU&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go get it at &lt;a href=&quot;http://alkualkualkualkualkualkualkualkualkualku.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ALKU99&quot; title=&quot;ALKU99&quot;&gt;ALKU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://x75.github.io/2016/08/16/rara-avis-out-on-alku/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://x75.github.io/2016/08/16/rara-avis-out-on-alku/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another test post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just saying hi while trying to acquire a jekyll habit.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://x75.github.io/2016/07/27/nothertestpost/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://x75.github.io/2016/07/27/nothertestpost/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Init post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; switch) to see your changes!
To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 16:42:30 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://x75.github.io/jekyll/update/2015/12/03/init/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://x75.github.io/jekyll/update/2015/12/03/init/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
