<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Always SWERVING to steer free of classically-minded mobs</title>
    <description>x75's blog, a dump for memes and sketches</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:42:14 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:42:14 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sound, music, sequences, search</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;sound-music-sequences-search&quot;&gt;Sound, music, sequences, search&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: sound, music, algorithms, generative models, sequence
models&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graphical dump of my current picture related to the relationships of
sound, music, sequences and search in corresponding spaces; incomplete
but more or less consistent [claim]. Domain layer in black, modelling
layer in green.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2018-08-14-Sound-music-sequences-search/aib-sound-music-sequences-search.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Graphical description of the scenery drawing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would like to argue that by combining &lt;em&gt;coding&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;latent space state
propagation&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;hierarchical composition&lt;/em&gt;, most of the phenomena in
sound, music, vocalization, spoken language, and written language can
be modelled, all with the same few items. Let me know if you think,
that this is obvious. Taking language as variable length sequences of
actions, this can be extended straightforwardly to model navigation
problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
References: autopop, augmented creativity, augmented editing,
teaching, game sounds, sonification, information sound scapes.
--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;

/**
*  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
*  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables*/
/*
var disqus_config = function () {
this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
};
*/
(function() { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE
var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');
s.src = '//x75.disqus.com/embed.js';
s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
(d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
})();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.1&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;fn.1&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/14/Sound-music-sequences-search/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/08/14/Sound-music-sequences-search/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unsorted recommended reading</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;unsorted-recommended-reading&quot;&gt;Unsorted recommended reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: books, motivation, complexity, growth, explanation,
predictive brain, network theory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just a quick dump of thoughts I can refer to and reduce repetition in
conversation. The books: &lt;strong&gt;Scale&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;EoA&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Pib&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime by the end of 2017 I picked up a tweet pushing Geoffrey
West’s 2017 book: &lt;strong&gt;Scale&lt;/strong&gt; - the universal laws of life and death in
organisms, cities, and companies. This immediately rang with me by
promising hot food regarding complexity, long-tailed distributions,
failure and growth. By that time I was already hyper-alert about
growth and pieces of growth related theory, based on its role in
development and learning (Refs: Pask, 1959, Physical analogues to the
growth of a concept). Current working hypothesis is, that &lt;strong&gt;open-ended
learning processes&lt;/strong&gt; can be seen as &lt;strong&gt;growth processes&lt;/strong&gt;. A theory of
growth should allow predictions about the preconditions, expected
learning speed, expected learning time and upper bounds of
learning. This is of course highly relevant when building curious,
self-aware, exploration agents and robots. Overt physical growth
appears to occur in the three-dimensional space of intuitive
experience. Alas, intuitive experience is itself an emergent
phenomenon of accumulated growth, and thus is probably significantly
mistaken about the character of the natural information space of any
given instance of a growth process. Many of you will recognize this as
another way of stating the &lt;em&gt;manifold hypothesis&lt;/em&gt;. In summary, this
allows to model learning as the growth of explanation, obtained
through the accumulated information “precipitating” from an active
search process (aka stochastic optimization). Growth is provided
energy in terms of different resources from an underlying
implementation fabric (power, memory, time constraints); it is driven
by a need of explanation of experience, sufficient with respect to a
given motivation; implemented by equating explanation of experience
with actions, and by observing their adequacy; adequacy is estimated
via different exploration stratgies; finally growth is limited by
finite time horizons, uncertainty, inherent total complexity, and
again, resources. The explanation-action equality is one of several
useful consequences of the predictive brain hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book has a lot of fundamentals, examples, and pointers to more
detailed material on all of this. Main research questions I’m taking
home from the angle of developmental learning and robots are: how can
the properties of space-filling-ness and impedance be brought to work
on information flow in dynamic inferential circuits (aka adaptive
models); and what is the relation of these properties to modularity in
model space. Obviously module types and available sizes should support
impedance matching, coverage, learning speed, and scaling, besides
reuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from this specific research perspective, on the basis of my
individual knowledge the book was smooth to read, and provided a huge
amount of highly informative reaffirmations, additional perspectives
and entirely novel concepts with immediate practical applicability in
everyday social, ecological, and ultimately psychological questions,
e.g. urban life, mass phenomena, one’s own resources, teams and
management, communication and marketing, attention, information
spread, opinions, and so on, scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very happy having finally ingested a long time resident of my to-read
stack, Georg Franck, 1998, Die &lt;strong&gt;Ökonomie der Aufmerksamkeit&lt;/strong&gt;,
Hanser, originally recommended to me by Otto Rössler in 2012. The book
seems to be available only in German on paper, but googling the ad-hoc
translation of the title should reveal a few english language
articles, which are much more compact than the book, so you’re
lucky. Interestingly, the meaning of the German “Aufmerksamkeit” has
no direct correspondence in English and falls apart into the two
distinct terms of attention and awareness. Attention emphasizes the
outward direction and the objects of the process, while awareness
encodes the inward direction and the subject of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Franck is a rare proponent of the radical privateness assumption about
subjective experience, probably necessary for effective self-models
and theories of mind in embodied agents and real world robots. This is
based on an extended version of Leibniz’s monads and implies, that
there is no way in principle for any agent to obtain the ground truth
about any other agent’s experience, ever. All information about the
experience of another has to be channelled through behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting attuned to the idiosyncracies, the book really takes off
and turns out to be written in beautifully precise and funny German
prose, imho. Again for me, it provided two essential assets to take
immediately. The first one is a thourough and explicit analysis of the
flow of attention in agent interaction, creating a powerful
explanation that simplifies several classically disparate phenomena by
the unifying them in a single framework by leveraging economical
methods of the analysis of behaviour. A welcome side effect of this is
a reference refutation of rational agents in classical game theory and
mainstream economic theory, that continues to fail so superbly over
the consequences of ignoring issues of the rational agent
assumption. Rationality can only be optimal in bounded linear
domains. In all others, where observability, dimensionality and
non-linearity combine to set a bound on the principal predictability,
irrational moves, more often called randomness, are more often than
not beneficial the agent’s long-term well-being. For in-depth
disussions of the limits of naive application of the optimality
principle, see for example Loeb, 2012, Optimal isn’t good enough;
Iigaya et al, 2017, Learning fast and slow: deviations from the
matching law can reflect an optimal strategy under uncertainty; tbc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of practical advice, guidance and inspiration can be found on
the tactical and strategic level valid in almost all domains requiring
systematic communication on any level. In particular, it includes an
analysis of the self-referential level of motivation and
self-storytelling, and extends upwards to all levels of social
relationships from dyadic, families, extended families, teams, teams
of teams, to supercritical phenomena like mass media and large scale
social networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recurring example and workhorse for the theory is the science it
self. I would expect that anyone involved with science and its
orthodox implementations on a professional level will shop one or more
insights into the processes of the science market, allowing new kinds
of power moves. Or so. Anyway, need to run, tbc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;

/**
*  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
*  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables*/
/*
var disqus_config = function () {
this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
};
*/
(function() { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE
var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');
s.src = '//x75.disqus.com/embed.js';
s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
(d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
})();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.1&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;fn.1&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/08/Hot-books/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/08/08/Hot-books/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Goals and carrots</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;goals-and-carrots-wip&quot;&gt;Goals and carrots [WIP]&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: motivation, temporal horizon, discount factor, policies,
complexity, management, self-organization, failure, creativity, open
culture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reflection, it currently appears to me, that the source of my
motivation is &lt;em&gt;beauty&lt;/em&gt; which comes quite close to something like
&lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt;. In mathematics, beauty has long been identified as a
lighthouse guiding search in high-dimensional darkness. Then meaning
is something that beauty can acquire by being applied in the real
world for its own sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is straightforward to identify a number major challenges that all
of us humans are facing on a global level, with all of us in it
together in a joint future. These challenges are of ecological,
social, and economic nature and are characterized throughout by
&lt;em&gt;complexity&lt;/em&gt;, a thing which we are just able to identify, and just
beginning to understand and take serious, although with a long history
of ideas attached (Refs: Gell-Mann: The Quark and the Jaguar, ). This
understanding should be available on a collective level to inform
policy making. Policies are recipes for action put down in a
table. Each situation that can be encountered should have a line in
the table and the corresponding entry in that line tells you what to
do in this situation. Sound knowledge of policy making should be
available at all levels of human activity, starting from individuals,
out through families, organizations, communities, regions, countries,
up to planetary scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignoring complexity issues usually leads to any of a wide array of
possible fails with quite variable impact (Refs: Clausewitz: the
essential unpredictability of war, the fog of war, “friction” – the
disparity between the ideal performance of units, organisation or
systems and their actual performance in real world scenarios (Book I,
Chapter VII), Dörner, 1997: The Logic Of Failure: Recognizing And
Avoiding Error In Complex Situations; Taleb, 2008: The Impact of the
Highly Improbable; Trivers, 2011, Deceit and self-deception: Fooling
yourself the better to fool others; tbc). Classic examples include the
release of rabbits in australia, the Cobra effect, and so on. Apart
from particular technical approaches to immediate concerns,
e.g. automated driving, education, elderly care, environmental
cleaning jobs, and so on, AI surely has cooperative potential for
augmenting human capacity and provide systematic contribution to
policy making at all relevant levels of small, medium, and large,
e.g. the individual, communal, regional and global levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would like to contribute to peeling out the cooperative and
augmenting aspects. As a team we are facing several complex problems,
for example the self-management of a geographically distributed
team. Since this is a really big one, it cannot be expected to be
“solved” anywhere soon, so it’s necessary to default to effective
heuristics and some glue to build approximate solution. I will start
by listing and briefly describing some heuristics that appear
promising to me, touching on the following items: open culture,
transparency, empowerment, local autonomy, self responsibility,
attention, credibility, past / future horizons, variability, local
minima, optimality in non-stationary environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first one is openness. In my experience, this is of fundamental
importance and I have become a proponent of radical openness, but I am
aware that the appeal is not always intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic argument is about the cost of closedness (see also and
expand: hidden cost, true cost). This cost is just not considered in
closed approaches, which clearly is negligent and careless. We have to
be aware that we are working with knowledge, and the beginning of
knowledge are ideas. Ideas are not isolated, standalone entities but
have to be considered on an ecological level. They are born and live
in an ecosystem of knowledge and ideas, and critically depend on each
other. The classical quote about “standing on the shoulders of giants”
&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fnr.1&quot; class=&quot;footref&quot; href=&quot;#fn.1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is just
about that. This means, we depend on access to ideas of others, and
fostering the ideas of others depends on sharing your own ideas. The
actual success of any particular enterprise hinges on a few very small
detailed modifications on knowledge widely available to everyone else
(FIXME: history of innovation with examples).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t worry about people stealing your ideas. If your ideas are any
good, you’ll have to ram them down people’s throats. – Howard
Aiken &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fnr.2&quot; class=&quot;footref&quot; href=&quot;#fn.2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is fully coherent with my own experience, allowing the vanity of
having had at least one good idea at some point. Keeping things closed
and proprietary thus incurs large cost. There is the immediate cost of
securing access to code and documents, the cost of complicating
publishing and deployment, and the longer term cost of impeding
evaluation and weeding out of bad ideas through discourse with
others. In the end, “closing” things in a complex world is impossible,
and basically it amounts to “obscuring” things. Then we know, security
by obscurity does not work in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Security experts have rejected this view as far back as 1851, and
advise that obscurity should never be the only security mechanism. –
Wikipedia &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fnr.3&quot; class=&quot;footref&quot; href=&quot;#fn.3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reinterpreting security as a kind of robustness to “attack”, a good
heuristic can be gleaned from biology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-in-progress-wip&quot;&gt;Work-in-progress [WIP]&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed&lt;/strong&gt; repesentation / biology: not one organ, not one
function (Monod?), &lt;strong&gt;Empowerment&lt;/strong&gt;: empower others to elevate yourself
in their wake?, &lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;/strong&gt;, local autonomy, responsibility, Team
of teams, &lt;strong&gt;Uncertain&lt;/strong&gt; future. Horizons. Discount
factor. n-step. predictive information. local minima. variability,
discount factor &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fnr.4&quot; class=&quot;footref&quot; href=&quot;#fn.4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Attention / awareness&lt;/strong&gt; G. Franck,
&lt;strong&gt;Credibility&lt;/strong&gt; (Trouble: F***‘in with a real one, no quests)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More refs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cobra effect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The myth of the objective, usefulness of useless knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team of teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Economy of attention&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The quark and the jaguar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Die Logik des Misslingens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black swan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Self-deceit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;

/**
*  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
*  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables*/
/*
var disqus_config = function () {
this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
};
*/
(function() { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE
var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');
s.src = '//x75.disqus.com/embed.js';
s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
(d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
})();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.1&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Newton?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.2&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Howard_H._Aiken&quot;&gt;https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Howard_H._Aiken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.3&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_through_obscurity&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_through_obscurity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.4&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://stats.stackexchange.com/questions/221402/understanding-the-role-of-the-discount-factor-in-reinforcement-learning&quot;&gt;https://stats.stackexchange.com/questions/221402/understanding-the-role-of-the-discount-factor-in-reinforcement-learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/23/goals-and-carrots/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/06/23/goals-and-carrots/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minecraft</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;minecraft-is-great-wip&quot;&gt;Minecraft is great [wip]&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: minecraft, open world, graphical, games&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malmo&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/project-malmo/&quot;&gt;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/project-malmo/&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Microsoft/malmo&quot;&gt;https://github.com/Microsoft/malmo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip install minecraft_data minecraftmap nbt2yaml PyNBT PyCraft picraft&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salge et al’s work on &lt;strong&gt;generative design&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1803.09853&quot;&gt;http://arxiv.org/abs/1803.09853&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://gendesignmc.engineering.nyu.edu/&quot;&gt;http://gendesignmc.engineering.nyu.edu/&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mcgreentn/GDMC&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mcgreentn/GDMC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;

/**
*  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
*  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables*/
/*
var disqus_config = function () {
this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
};
*/
(function() { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE
var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');
s.src = '//x75.disqus.com/embed.js';
s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
(d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
})();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/05/minecraft/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/12/05/minecraft/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>python for MIDI</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;python-tools-for-midi&quot;&gt;python tools for midi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: python, music, midi, score, event representation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the best is the non-python &lt;strong&gt;midicsv&lt;/strong&gt;,
http://www.fourmilab.ch/webtools/midicsv/ which reads the midifile and
dumps it into a nice table of comma-separated values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some python candidate packages for working with MIDI, essentially reading and parsing MIDI files but musicology can be put on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mido&lt;/strong&gt; - MIDI Objects for Python, https://github.com/olemb/mido&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Mido is a library for working with MIDI messages and ports. It’s designed to be as straight forward and Pythonic as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docs: https://mido.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python MIDI&lt;/strong&gt;, https://github.com/vishnubob/python-midi,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Python, for all its amazing ability out of the box, does not provide you with an easy means to manipulate MIDI data. There are probably about ten different python packages out there that accomplish some part of this goal, but there is nothing that is totally comprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This toolkit aims to fulfill this goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;music21&lt;/strong&gt;: a toolkit for computer-aided musicology, http://web.mit.edu/music21/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Music21 is a set of tools for helping scholars and other active listeners answer questions about music quickly and simply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mingus&lt;/strong&gt;, https://github.com/bspaans/python-mingus, Docs: http://bspaans.github.io/python-mingus/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;mingus is a package for Python used by programmers, musicians, composers and researchers to make and analyse music&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result&lt;/strong&gt;: Pip installed all four of them without issues, music21 nags about running in python2, loaded and dumped some midi data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open ends&lt;/strong&gt;: musicxml, configure music21 with all helper programs, workflows for some common conversion tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;

/**
*  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
*  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables*/
/*
var disqus_config = function () {
this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
};
*/
(function() { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE
var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');
s.src = '//x75.disqus.com/embed.js';
s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
(d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
})();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/29/python-midi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/29/python-midi/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From snowboarding to motion, music, and robotics</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-snowboarding-to-motion-music-and-robotics&quot;&gt;From snowboarding to motion, music, and robotics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: motion, robot learning, exploration, music, bio-inspiration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently while browsing my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redbulletin.com/at/de/the-red-bulletin-magazin&quot;&gt;favorite robotics
magazine&lt;/a&gt;
I started reading an interview with Travis Rice, previously unknown to
me, promoting his recent film &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefourthphase.com/&quot;&gt;The Fourth
Phase&lt;/a&gt;. It’s usual that athletes
mention issues interesting to robotics when talking about their body
and the challenges involved in particular stunts, which is the reason
why RB in fact is my fav’ed robotics mag in the first place. What
struck me about this interview, though, is that Travis just didn’t
stop dropping major agreeable insights about motion and environments
and possible responses of an agent. Sorry for the german text, here’s
the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redbulletin.com/uk/en/sports/travis-rices-quest-for-the-ultimate-snowboard-adventure&quot;&gt;english version of the
interview&lt;/a&gt;
which seems nicer in the formulations anyway ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/20161109_rb_rice/rbrice_01_IMG_20161103_091430_400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Snowboarding and music&quot; title=&quot;Snowboarding and music&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is about adaptive rhythms which &lt;em&gt;play&lt;/em&gt; with the topographic
situation and the transitions between local configurations, the result
being a combination of the influences of the environment and the
individual response. The same evaluation criteria seem to apply for
music and motion in terms of the &lt;em&gt;groove&lt;/em&gt;. Would be nice if we could
capture that as a loss criterion for learning motions, like, what is
a nice dance for a given song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/20161109_rb_rice/rbrice_02_IMG_20161103_091444_400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Topography, saliency, navigation&quot; title=&quot;Topography, saliency, navigation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we need errors to do any actual learning, no problem. Then this
is about picking salient features of the topography, landmarks, as
reference points to attach triggers for specific action sequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/20161109_rb_rice/rbrice_03_IMG_20161103_091455_400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flow, reaction speed and mental simulation&quot; title=&quot;Flow, reaction speed and mental simulation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adequate reaction speed requires a flow-state which means very little
or zero conscious participation in the motion control. Not sure about
the fear stuff in the context of robotics. Finally, mental simulation
is being used for finding an action sequence that copes with some
topographic situation and is being pushed down during the simulations
into low-level action control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/20161109_rb_rice/rbrice_04_IMG_20161103_091506_400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Search objectives, exploration&quot; title=&quot;Search objectives, exploration&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is about search criteria where you are trying to find features
that provoke motion solutions which are supposed to be rewarding in
the musical sense, which provides inspiration for interesting
exploration objectives for robots (“… geological oddities. We want
weird. Weird is good”). Actively seek out environmental and perceptual
challenges such that entirely new behaviour needs to be generated in
response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/20161109_rb_rice/rbrice_05_IMG_20161103_091511_400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Motivations, objectives&quot; title=&quot;Motivations, objectives&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding an &lt;em&gt;answer&lt;/em&gt; to weird and unusual environmental stimuli that
you have sought out earlier using the weirdness search objective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers, let’s move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;

/**
*  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
*  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables*/
/*
var disqus_config = function () {
this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
};
*/
(function() { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE
var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');
s.src = '//x75.disqus.com/embed.js';
s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
(d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
})();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/11/09/motion-music-robotics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/11/09/motion-music-robotics/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apparent uselessness</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;apparent-uselessness-the-illusion-of-progress-and-the-difficulty-of-finding-your-way&quot;&gt;Apparent uselessness, the illusion of progress, and the difficulty of finding your way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: robot epistemology, robot learning, exploration, dominant progressivist narratives, undreamed-of-utility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime last year I picked up on Kenneth Stanley’s and Joel Lehmann’s
2015 book called &lt;a href=&quot;http://mythoftheobjective.com/&quot;&gt;Why Greatness Cannot Be Planned - The Myth of the
Objective&lt;/a&gt;. In the book they develop an argument for an advanced
teleology based on experiments with synthetic processes of knowledge
acquisition in the context of AI, ALife, and Learning. The argument
roughly says, that if you want to reach a goal, that is ambitious in
the sense that the &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; sequence of steps (the route) which will
get you there, is not known, then accumulating possible steps is a
better strategy than heading directly into the direction of the
goal. That’s because chances are, that some of these steps will turn
out, but unforseeably so, to be precisely what is needed to make the
next move when negotiating the route. So far so good, I agree with this line of reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, additional manifestations of that same idea keep
popping up urging the collector inside me to collect. Here we
go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt; Stanley and Lehmann argue that, considering results on
“novelty search” in learning experiments with artificial agents,
unreflected measures of the distance to a given “goal” are bound to
get you stuck in a local extremum in all but trivial cases &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1939&lt;/strong&gt; Abraham Flexner’s article “The usefulness of useless
knowledge” &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, published in Harper’s issue 179 June/November 1939 (available online as &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.ias.edu/files/UsefulnessHarpers.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;). Flexner curiously sketches out a similar line of argument as
Stanley and Lehmann reinvigorating satisfaction of &lt;em&gt;curiosity&lt;/em&gt; as a sufficient and ultimately fruitful guide in the pursuit of knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;198X&lt;/strong&gt; The field of media archaeology has been promoting the stance
that complex techno-mathematical media can only be understood by
reconstructing original forward-looking perspectives and
emphasizing the genealogical importance of developments which
became “dead media” only in hindsight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt; Nicholas Nassim Taleb, deserving a separate comment on the black
swan idea (2007), meticulously expounds the difference of the
forward and the retrospective narration and substantializes the
phenomenon of unpredictability in the domain of complex systems (Extremistan). Honouring
this fundamental unpredictabilty we should be highly doubtful
about our ability to predict the future utility of any given idea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is an open list and this entry is a placeholder for things to
come …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realizing the validity of this issue there are fundamental
consequences for many areas of human activity, two of which are:
autonomous robotic learning (no universal recipe) and funding of
professional and amateur scientific pursuits (no maps for uncharted
territory &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spectrum-of-difficulties-in-reaching-goals&quot;&gt;Spectrum of difficulties in reaching goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on my own understanding of different learning problems for
artificial agents there exists a spectrum of difficulty, open to the
top, along which learning tasks can be positioned. In that spectrum we
can draw a line somewhere separating two types of such
problems. &lt;strong&gt;Update [2016-11-03]&lt;/strong&gt;: There is a direct correspondence here
with the complexity of functional relationships which could be ordered
like linear, monotonic, non-monotonic, zero/random. The line that I am
referring to above goes through the spectrum between monotonic and
non-monotonic problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are those problems, in which the goal-seeker (agent) and the
goal are alone in “free space”, meaning that the goal is visible to
the agent and the goal can be reached by following a monotonic
gradient, that is, by greedily reducing the distance on all axes of
space independently, reducing the problem to finding out about the
effects of the primitive actions (SMP) available to the agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other type are those in which other objects, usually referred to
as obstacles, are present in the same space. Here already no universal
recipe whatsoever can be given on how to reach the goal without
exploring the space first and building a map. In order to reach a goal
or desired destination, the distance to the goal has to increase on at
least one axis of the given space at some point
(non-monotonicity). This means, that if the wrong distance measure is
used, you easily end up in a local extremum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue also seems related to a) convexity, leaving the respective
reasoning and diagram as an exercise for a possible later post, and b)
to Franz &amp;amp; Mallot’s navigation hierarchy from their 2000 paper &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;

/**
*  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
*  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables*/
/*
var disqus_config = function () {
this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
};
*/
(function() { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE
var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');
s.src = '//x75.disqus.com/embed.js';
s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
(d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
})();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;#spectrum-of-difficulties-in-reaching-goals&quot;&gt;this section&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Thanks Giulio Sandini.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Please describe in precise steps how you are going to reach an
objective (draw a route on a map), which at best is likely to exist
and usually is only a vision, and where no one has gone before (on
parts of the map labelled “Terra incognita”).&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Biomimetic robot navigation. M. Franz, and H. Mallot. Robotics and Autonomous Systems 30 (1-2): 133-153 (2000)&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/10/06/apparent-uselessness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/10/06/apparent-uselessness/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rara Avis out on ALKU, ALKU099</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;rara-avis-music-cassette-mc-and-booklet-both-screaming-yellow-out-now-on-alku&quot;&gt;Rara Avis Music Cassette (MC) and booklet, both screaming yellow, out now on ALKU&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go get it at &lt;a href=&quot;http://alkualkualkualkualkualkualkualkualkualku.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ALKU99&quot; title=&quot;ALKU99&quot;&gt;ALKU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/16/rara-avis-out-on-alku/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/08/16/rara-avis-out-on-alku/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another test post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just saying hi while trying to acquire a jekyll habit.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/07/27/nothertestpost/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/07/27/nothertestpost/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Init post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; switch) to see your changes!
To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 16:42:30 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2015/12/03/init/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2015/12/03/init/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
